让我们用模拟来制作一些酷炫的家具。
Let's make some cool furniture with simulations.
我将从创建一个平面开始，这样我们就可以在那设置一个碰撞体。
So I'm going to start by making a plane so we can have a collider there.
我要隐藏摄像机，因为我现在不想让它打扰我。
I'm going to hide the camera because I don't want that to bother me right now.
现在我要做的是创建一些有机且抽象的东西。
Right now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to create something that feels organic and abstract.
想象一下，你走进一家博物馆，在入口大厅看到一张巨大的沙发。
Imagine that you enter a museum and you see a big sofa that's in the entrance hall.
这就是我们要做的事情。
So that's what we're going to do.
然后也许我们可以尝试做一些在某种程度上更贴近现实的东西。
And then after that maybe we can look at doing something that feels a little more grounded in reality in a way.
比如说，一张扶手椅。
Something like an armchair for example.
所以我要做的是选择一个样条线。
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab a spline.
切换到顶部视图。
Let's go to top view.
顺便说一下，我还是很怀念那些图标。
By the way, I still miss the icons for that stuff.
让我们快速画一个样条线。
Let's make a quick spline.
我不会太注重细节，因为我们可能会对它进行优化。
I'm not going to get too much into detail because we'll probably refine it anyway.
切换回透视视图。
Let's go back to perspective.
我不想看到灯光，也不想看到任何其他东西。
I don't want to see lights, I don't want to see anything.
把它稍微移动到中间一点。
Let's move it a little bit towards the middle.
嗯，看起来还不错。
Yeah, it's not looking that bad.
目前没什么需要担心的。
Nothing to worry about at this moment.
那么让我们翻转这个家伙。
So let's flip this bad boy.
添加一个圆。
Let's add a circle.
嗯，我们有这个。
And well, we have this.
你可能会觉得这个没用。
And you'll think this is useless.
嗯，现在确实是没用。
Well, it is now.
我们试着加一些杯子。
Let's try to add some cups.
抱歉，背景里有狗在叫。
Sorry, the dog is barking in the background.
所以一切看起来更圆润了。
So everything is more rounded.
老实说，我对这里的交叉不是特别担心，因为我可能会把它放到一个边界断裂中。
Honestly, I'm not too worried about intersections here because I would probably put this into a borderline fracture anyway.
但我担心这里的这个部分。
But I'm worried about this part here.
我们把它做成一个软插值。
Let's make it a soft interpolation.
老实说，我只是想稍微调整一下，因为
Honestly, I'm just going to tweak it a little bit because
我不知道。我有点喜欢它碰撞的感觉，因为一旦你把它放进体积测量中，它看起来会有点像皱纹的效果。
I don't know. I kind of like it when it collides because once you drop it into the volume measure, it looks like it has some kind of wrinkles in a way.
是的，我们不必担心它太靠近，因为通过模拟，它最终会扩展开来。
Yeah, we don't have to worry about it being too close because with the simulation, it's eventually going to expand.
所以我们把它放到一个边界断裂中。
So let's drop this into a borderline fracture.
是的，我们得到了这种模式，但这并不是我们想要的。
And yeah, we have this kind of pattern, which is not exactly what we are looking for.
现在，我要尝试用这个点生成器分布。
Right now, I'm going to try and use it with this point generator distribution.
我不想有太多的切割，因为切割越多，看起来就越不真实。
I don't want to have a lot of cuts because the more we have, the less realistic it's going to look.
所以我们选三个。
So let's go for three.
然后我们稍微偏移一下碎片，这样它们之间会有一些间距。
And let's offset the fragments a little bit so we have some spacing in between them.
好的，我觉得这个可以行得通。
So, okay, I think this can work.
我们继续往前推进吧。
Let's just keep moving forward.
我们重新合并一下。
Let's remerge that.
这样我们开始有更多四边形的几何结构了。
So we are starting to have more quad geometry.
虽然它不是完美的，但可能适合我们的用途。
Even though it's not perfect, it will probably work for our purposes.
我们可以在这里再细分一点。
We could either subdivide it here a bit more.
我觉得我实际上会两者都做。
I think I'm going to actually do both.
然后可能我们也需要在这里进行细分。
And then maybe we need to actually subdivide it here too.
但可能不需要太多。
But maybe not as much.
我们就用这个试试看效果吧。
Let's give it a go with this and see how it looks.
接下来我们去模拟一下。
So we are going to go and simulate this.
给某个地方加上布料。
Let's put a cloth of somebody.
我们试试用布料。
Let's try with the cloth.
因为我们实际上需要它变成一个气球。
Because we actually need it to be a balloon.
我们需要添加一些过压让它膨胀起来。
And we need to add some overpressure so it grows.
回到第零帧。
Go to frame zero.
我觉得它有效。
I think it works.
这其实有点扫兴。
This is actually a little bit of a bummer.
如果你禁用了这个，它是不会起作用的。
If you have this disabled, it won't work.
好吧，看起来糟透了。
Okay, looks like shit.
我们给地面添加一个碰撞器。
Let's add a collider to the ground.
看起来没那么糟了。
It's not looking as bad.
相信我，情况可能会更糟。
Trust me, it could be worse.
我觉得可能是我们有太多的过压，而且发生得太快了。
I think that maybe we have a lot of overpressure and it's happening too quick maybe.
所以可能我们需要75帧。
So maybe we are going to need 75 frames.
现在我们试试用一些更微妙的方式。
Let's try with something that feels subtler for now.
好的。
Okay.
嗯，这稍微好一点了。
Yeah, that's a little bit better.
其实，你知道吗
Actually, you know what
也许值得一试。
Maybe it will be worth
这里发生了什么事情？
What's going on here
好吧，这样永远行不通。
Okay, this is never going to work.
嗯，我们已经完成了这个。
Well, we have this done.
我们很快会修好的。
We'll fix it in a second.
但我要做的是移除重力。
But what I'm going to do is I'm going to remove the gravity.
我们还需要检查这个家伙。
And we need to check this motherfucker.
还记得我说过的关于那个角落看起来很棒之类的话吗？
So remember everything that I said about that corner looking great and blah blah
嗯，实际上我们需要修复它。
Well, we actually need to fix it.
好吧，我们再试一次。
Okay, let's try again.
好吧，这次好一些了。
Okay, this is better.
没有任何重力的话，模拟会更好。
Without any gravity, it's going to be just better to simulate it.
但正如你所见，东西正在消失。
But as you can see, things are going away.
这是一个有趣的模拟，但现在来说完全没用。
It's a fun simulation, but absolutely worthless as it is right now.
所以我们需要做的是添加一些混合动画。
So what we need to do is that we need to add some mixed animation.
而我喜欢做的是通过施加力来实现。
And what I like to do is I put it by force.
如果你将其设置为1，它会尝试保持原位。
And if you set it to just one, it will try to keep its place.
所以你现在可以看到，一切都保持在原位，这真的很酷。
So as you can see now, everything stays in the same place, which is really cool.
也许我们可以开始试验一下，如果我们想要一些褶皱之类的效果。
And maybe we can start experimenting with this if we want to get some wrinkles and stuff like that.
嗯，我们得到了这个抽象的形状。
Well, we are getting this abstract shape.
老实说，我现在不是很喜欢它，但有一件事我们可以做也应该做。
Honestly, not a fan of it right now, but one thing that we can and we should do
首先，让我们把目标长度调高一点，这样我们也会得到更多褶皱。
First of all, let's put the target length a little bit higher so we get more wrinkles too.
我觉得这可能会有点过，但我们必须试一下。
I think this is going to do too much, but we have to try.
嗯，是的，但我们开始在这里那里得到更多的褶皱。
Well, yeah, but we start to get some more wrinkles here and there.
确实可能我们需要更多的几何形状。
It's true that maybe we need some more geometry.
所以让我们试着去掉细分曲面。
So let's try to actually get rid of the subdivision surface.
我们可能稍后会需要它，但在我们完成模拟之后。
We will probably need it later, but once we have simulated.
当然，更多的多边形意味着速度会变慢，但模拟的分辨率会更加真实。
Of course, more polygons means it's going to be slower, but the resolution of the simulation is going to be more realistic.
是的，前几帧看起来更糟，但我们在各处得到了更多的细节。
Yeah, first frames are looking worse, but we are getting much more detail everywhere.
而且这开始看起来酷多了。
And this is starting to look much, much cooler.
我们实际上可以做的一件事是为了模拟人们实际坐下的地方。
One thing that we can do actually, it's in order to simulate where people will actually sit.
我喜欢在上面放一个碰撞体，它会是不可见的，但它将有助于在顶部创建更多的坐下区域。
I like to put a collider on top, which is going to be invisible, but it's going to be useful to create more of a sitting area on top.
假设我们喜欢这个效果。
And let's say we like it there.
如你所见，这样我们开始得到一些可以实际用作抽象沙发或类似物的东西。
As you can see, this way we are starting to get something that can be actually used as an abstract sofa or something like that.
可能我们需要在这里加一条边。
Probably we have to add an edge here.
这就是它出问题的原因。
That's why it's causing that.
所以也许我们可以尝试多加一些圆角，让各处都更加平滑一些。
So maybe we can try and add a little bit more fillet just so things are a little bit smoother everywhere.
我们把这个标记隐藏起来吧。
Let's hide this marker.
是的，你可以看到那部分现在好多了。
Yeah, you can see that part is much better now.
而且这些东西现在实际上可以被细分了。
And this stuff can be actually subdivided now.
我们得到了这种有机的形状。
And we have this kind of organic.
可能它的底部看起来也非常酷。
Probably the bottom of it is also looking really cool.
我们有这些非常非常酷且细节丰富的形状。
We have these really, really cool shapes with a lot of detail.
这些看起来很棒。
And these are looking amazing.
而且这些实际上可以应用到任何形状上。
And this can actually be applied to any kind of shape.
我只是用这种抽象的方式来做，因为我发现这样出来的结果会更酷一些。
I'm just doing it in this abstract way because I found that the results are a little bit cooler.
不过是的，这是一个非常抽象且酷炫的沙发。
But yeah, it's a really abstract and cool looking sofa.
不得不说我很喜欢它。我真的很喜欢。
I have to say I love it. I really love it.
所以这件事很酷的一点是它非常程序化。
So the cool thing about this is that it's quite procedural.
所以我要复制这个，并确保禁用掉模拟。
So I'm going to duplicate this and make sure that I disable the simulations.
酷的地方在于我们可以用它做任何我们想做的东西。
And the cool thing is that we can make whatever we want with it.
所以如果我们想开始移动这些东西，它会崩溃，因为这是Cinema 4D。
So if we want to start moving things around, it's going to crash because it's Cinema 4D.
其实是我的问题。我有很多东西。
It's on me, actually. I have a lot of stuff.
我们有硼耐火材料，这个我们还可以编辑。
So we have the boron refractory, which we can still edit.
我们可以尝试任意多种不同的形状。
And we can try as many different shapes as we want.
嗯，这部分看起来真的很棒。
Well, this part here is looking really lovely.
主要是这里的部分回到了那个，但可能是因为这个原因。
Mostly this part here goes back that, but well, probably because of this reason.
所以我们可以做的是把它放入一个体积中
So what we can do is actually put this inside a volume
我在干什么
What am I doing
体积生成器和体积测量。
Volume builder and a volume measure.
我们给它增加的不是空间，而是分辨率。
Let's give it more not space, but resolution.
我们可以试着看看它的效果。
And we can try and see this, how it looks.
我们现在有更多的三角形，所以模拟显得更加有机。
We have more triangles right now, so the simulation is way, way more organic.
但它有点模仿生长模拟，这也是真的太酷了。
But it kind of mimics a growth simulation, which is also really fucking sick.
也有点让人恶心。
It's a little bit disgusting, too.
哇，太酷了。
Wow, so sick.
我要截一张这个的静帧。
I'm going to grab a still of this.
棒极了。恶心，但很棒。
Lovely. Disgusting, but lovely.
如果我们对它进行细分，它会更紧密一点，但我们来看看。
And if we subdivide it, it's going to be a little bit tighter, but let's see.
是的，用它工作有点难以忍受。
Yeah, it's a little bit unbearable to work with.
但是它创造了一个非常非常有机的形状。
But it creates a really, really organic shape.
看看底部这一部分，看起来非常棒。
And look at this bottom part is looking so sick.
我觉得它实际上跳过了。
I think it has actually skipped
是的，它跳过了地面，因为我忘了在那儿放碰撞器。
Yeah, it has skipped the ground because I forgot to put the collider there.
但它在那儿创造的效果也很酷。
But it's also cool what it's creating there.
说实话，我真的得停止看它了。
To be fair, it's quite I have to stop looking at it.
看起来有点恶心。
It looks disgusting.
是的，几何体太多了，但没关系。
Yeah, too much geometry, but it's all right.
没关系。
It's all right.
这个技术的酷炫之处是你可以将它应用到这个样条上。
And the cool thing about this technique is that you can apply it to this spline.
你也可以把它应用到一些立方体上。
You can apply it to some cubes.
不过我们稍后再看看。
But let's see it in a second.
我现在要做的是尝试使用这个。
What I'm going to do now is I'm going to try and use this
让我看看。
Let me see.
我想把这个也做成我们的碰撞器。
I want to make this our collider, too.
所以也许看看吧，看看它如何运作。
So maybe let's see. Let's see how it works.
嗯，它们消失了。
Well, they disappear.
可能是因为我们添加了这个。
Probably once we've added this
我要把我们的东西放回去。
I'm going to put back ours.
体积测量可能需要稍微调整一下。
The volume measure maybe we need to tweak a little bit.
尤其是这个，因为它是制造所有皱纹的原因。
Especially this one because that's the one that's creating all the wrinkles.
虽然它们看起来不错，但可能不是我们目前想要的效果。
Which again, they are looking good, but probably not what we're looking for at the moment.
它们也消失得有点太快了。
They get a little bit lost too quick.
我打算尝试用这个圆。
What I'm going to try and do is I'm going to use this circle.
哦，糟了。
Oh, shit.
它变了。
It changes.
我们可以添加一个平面，让它们稍微大一点。
We can add a plane to make them a little bit bigger.
这只是为了测试目的。
This is just for testing purposes.
但是让我们看看它的效果。
But let's see how it looks.
不过这里还是有很多问题。
Again, we have a lot of issues here.
这些其他部分看起来很好，因为我们有这些链条在保持形状。
These other parts are looking great because we have these kind of chains that are keeping the shape together.
但是让我们试试，也许我们需要
But let's try, maybe we need to
实际上，我们也来做一件事。
Actually, also, let's do one thing.
我要创建这个主样条线的一个实例。
I'm going to create an instance of this main spline.
然后我会用创建这个的第二个替换它。
And I'm going to replace it with the second one that's creating this.
这样，如果我们修改一个样条线，就只需要改一次。
So that way, if we modify one spline, we just need to do it once.
让我们试着做一个更正常的
Let's try and make a more normal looking
不管这是什么。
Whatever this is.
我们也把这个禁用吧。
Let's disable this too.
还有重网格化器，也请禁用。
And also the remesher, please.
我在想，也许这里我们不需要重网格化器。
I'm thinking that probably we don't need the remesher here.
因为我们实际上把东西放进了
Because we are actually putting things inside the
整个图像里，无论如何。
The whole image, anyway.
你看，它稍微保持了那个形状。
You see, it's respecting that shape a little bit.
这里有点乱套了。
It's getting fucked up there.
但说实话，我觉得这就是Cinema 4D的局限性。
But honestly, I think that's like limitations from Cinema 4D.
确实，这些东西的分辨率也非常低。
It's true that also these guys here don't have a lot of resolution at all.
也许它们的几何体稍微多一点。
Maybe they have a little bit more geometry.
情况就不会那么糟了。
It won't be as bad.
不过，一开始它们就已经发生碰撞了。
But well, to begin with, they are even already colliding.
禁用平衡，就是这样。
Disable poise, that's it.
我不知道，我觉得它看起来真的很酷。
I don't know, I think it's looking really cool.
我喜欢它。
I love it.
让我们尝试一些其他奇怪的东西。
Let's try some other weird stuff.
我们开始稍微整理一下东西吧。
Let's start to organize things a little bit.
这个将是B2。
This is going to be B2.
这个是B1。
This is B1.
永远记得禁用所有的动态标签。
Always remember to disable all your dynamic tags.
否则，一切都会被模拟。
Otherwise, everything is going to be simulated.
比如这些东西。
For example, this stuff.
难道它不能被禁用吗？
Can't it be disabled
真是太糟糕了。
That fucking sucks.
太糟糕了。
Fucking sucks.
好吧，我打算退出了。
Well, I'm going to just remove myself.
实际上，如果你移除体积光标，会更好。
And actually, if you remove the volume cursor, that's going to be better.
否则，它会计算它。
Otherwise, it's going to calculate it.
这是我们正在使用的碰撞器。
And this is the collider that we are using.
这个可以是全局的，但我会为这个和那个各复制一次。
This can be global, but I'm going to duplicate it both times for this and this.
这样我就可以准确地跟踪所有正在发生的事情。
Just so I can keep track exactly of everything that's going on.
B1。
B1.
遗憾的是，我需要移除碰撞器标签。
Sadly, I need to remove the collider tag.
我们试着做一些感觉更正常的事情。
Let's try to do something that feels a little bit more normal in a way.
让我重复使用这个。
Let me reuse this.
我们最初使用的标签，我要把它启用。
The first tag that we were using, I'm going to enable it.
我只是按下去看看效果如何。
I'm just going to press hit to see how it is.
一个普通外观的垫子。
Your average looking cushion.
我们把它放到一个体积光标里。
Let's put it in a volume cursor.
我要尝试不同的形状。
I'm going to try different shapes.
我们或许可以把它放进一个对称模式，这样可以节省一些时间。
Let's put this in a symmetry maybe, so we are saving some time.
这看起来很糟糕，因为多边形太少了。
This looks like shit because it's too low poly.
实际上，现在我们正在创建一个增长效果，因为我们在体积光标内进行模拟。
Actually, right now we are creating a growth effect because we are simulating inside the volume cursor.
这实际上也是一个很酷的点可以检查。
This is actually also something cool to check.
你实际上是在创建一个增长效果，因为我们在模拟之后应用了体积测量。
You are actually creating a growth effect because we are simulating and then we are applying the volume measure.
这很酷，但我认为Cinema 4D还不足以完成这些模拟。
It's cool, but I don't think Cinema 4D is there to be able to pull up these simulations.
这其实相当酷，看起来像一个泡沫模拟。
It's actually quite cool. It can look like a foam simulation.
此时它们也在相互碰撞，因为实际上是三个不同的形状。
At this moment it's also colliding with each other because it's actually three different shapes.
结果其实挺酷的，但这不是我想要的。
The result is actually quite cool, but it's not what I was looking for.
我想要整体修改它。
I was looking to modify this as a whole.
现在这个平面不太好用，因为我们有一些东西在外面。
The plane right now is not working well for that reason because we have some stuff outside.
我们来试试另一个立方体，把它放进一个文件夹里。
Let's try another cube that we are going to put inside a folder.
我把这个放进文件夹是因为我喜欢把东西整理得整齐。
I'm putting this inside a folder because I like to keep things tidy.
所以每次我想要减去某些东西时，我只需要把它放进文件夹，这样会更容易操作。
So every time that I put something that I want to subtract, I can just put it inside of the folder and that's going to be much easier to work with.
很酷的东西。真的很酷。
Cool stuff. That's really cool.
让我们继续给这个奇怪的沙发添加形状。
Let's keep adding shapes to our weird looking sofa.
正如你现在看到的，在这个过程中我没有考虑形状的问题。
As you can see right now for this process I'm not taking into consideration anything about shapes.
我只是记住比例，这样我知道如果需要的话，这可以稍后应用到某些真实的东西上。
I'm just keeping in mind proportions so I know that this could later on be applied to something real if needed.
好了，一个漂亮的充气沙发。
There you go. A nice inflated sofa.
可能我们这个音频有点多了。对此感到抱歉。
Probably we have too much of this audio. Sorry about that.
如果你想让东西看起来更干净，你可以使用这些看起来也很有趣的形状。
If you want things to look cleaner you can have these kind of shapes that are looking super fun too.
否则这些形状真的很难做出来。
Otherwise these kind of shapes are really hard to pull up.
我觉得现在这个不太好看，但你可以调整一下，让它看起来更精致一点。
I think right now this is not so beautiful but you can tweak things just to make it look a little bit more refined I guess.
公平地说，我不会怪任何人，只能怪我自己，因为我用的形状非常丑。
Now to be fair, I won't blame anyone but myself because the shape that I'm using is super ugly.
一点意义都没有。
It makes no sense at all.
比例都没问题，所以我要稍微调整一下，这样我们就能得到一个看起来更精致的东西。
The proportions are all well that's why I'm going to tweak it a little bit so we got something that looks a little bit more refined.
我们来试试这样做。
Let's try something like this.
我的意思是，这看起来更酷了。
I mean this is looking cooler.
我们加一点压力。
Let's add a little bit more pressure.
一点这个，一点那个。
A little bit of this, a little bit of that.
喜欢这个。看起来好多了。
Love it. This is looking much better.
现在我要做的是用我们这里的这些形状，创建一些碰撞器来作为我们椅子的基础。
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to use these shapes that we have here and I'm going to create some colliders to act like the base of our chair.
例如，如果我们复制这两个
So for example if we duplicate these two
我的意思是，这在现实生活中要给出一点背景会很难。
I mean this is going to be hard to give a little context like in real life.
但我们绝对可以试着让它更贴近现实一些。
But we can definitely try to make it feel a little bit more grounded in reality.
好吧，那我们现在就这么做。
So yeah, let's do this for now.
或许之后我们可以在需要时连接这些东西。
Maybe then we can connect things if we need.
看看它会不会坏。
Let's see if it doesn't break.
好吧，它坏了。
Okay, it broke.
我觉得一开始它是有效的。
I think it worked at the beginning.
是的，但后来它完全忽略了我们的
Yeah, but then it totally ignored our
我们施加的压力太大了，所以试试用三个。
We have too much pressure going on so let's try with three.
它完全被忽略了。
It got absolutely ignored.
让我快速试一下
Let me try to quickly
实际上，让我试试。
Actually, let me try.
是的，我觉得它根本就没起作用。
Yeah, I think it wasn't just working at all.
我们需要针对每一个进行处理。
We need to attack for each of them.
其实这个，我要把它做出来
Actually this one, I'm going to make it
你可以看到，这个形状在另一个形状里面。
And you can see you have this shape inside of this other shape.
看起来真的很酷。
It's just looking really cool.
不过，说实话我不是很喜欢这个形状，因为它看起来有点蠢。
Well, I'm not a super fan of this shape because it looks a little bit stupid to be fair.
但是你可以继续试试
But you can go ahead and also
我想我弄坏了。
I think I broke it.
是的，我弄坏了。
Yeah, I broke it.
我弄坏了，因为现在这是我们最初的几何体，不过，这没什么关系。
I broke it because now this is our initial geometry, but well, it doesn't really matter.
所以，比如说，也许我们现在可以这样做，假设这是我们的形状。
So, for example, maybe what we can do right now, let's say this is our shape.
我们可以这样放置它，否则如果它再往前就会发生碰撞。
We can either put it like this or it's going to collide if it goes farther.
不过现在情况有点失控了。
But things are going crazy right now.
我们确实需要更多的碰撞体，这是肯定的。
And we need some more colliders there, that's for sure.
所以让我们试着把碰撞体加回来。
So let's try to bring back the collider.
我想从这个形状中烘焙出一个形状。
And I want to bake a shape out of this one.
然后我要
And I'm going to
哎呀，这里发生了什么
Oops, what's happening here
可能我们到处都有更多的碰撞体。
Probably we have more colliders everywhere.
是的，这真糟糕。
Yeah, that sucks.
是的，我认为这样效果更好。
Yeah, I think that works better.
所以也许我们不需要这个巨大的碰撞体。
So maybe we don't want this huge collider.
让我们试试把它放在一个位置，这样我们就可以创建
Let's try and put this in a way so we can create
想象一下这是一个长椅。
Imagine this is a bench.
我想把那部分移到这里，这部分移到那里。
And I want that part there to be this part here and this part here.
这样我就可以在两个地方创建一个座位区。
So I can create a sitting area in both places.
嗯，这看起来不错。
Yeah, that's looking good.
让我截取这个形状的静态图。
And let me get a still of this shape.
枫木和
Maple and
好的，所以我们把这个作为主要的起始基础。
Okay, so we have this as our main starting base.
我们来尝试稍微修复一下几何形状。
Let's try to fix the geometry a little bit.
也许我们可以给它添加一个平滑效果。
Maybe we can put a smooth on it.
这样可以更好地控制这些褶皱。
And have a little bit more control on those wrinkles.
你可以看到它之前是这样的。
You can see it was like this.
也许字体标签本身也可以发挥作用。
Maybe the font tag itself could work anyway.
但我认为它也可以被使用。
But I think it can be used also.
这里有一个平滑变形器。
There's a smoothing deformer.
我们有一个奇怪的座位区。
We have this weird sitting area.
看起来很棒。
It's looking great.
这个底部部分看起来更酷了。
This bottom part is looking even cooler.
实际上，我刚刚有了一个想法。
And actually, I just had an idea.
实际上，这种形状也可以用于3D打印。
This can actually also be used for 3D printing as the kind of shape that it's creating.
例如，这可以用作钥匙扣。
This can be used, for example, as a keyholder.
好的，我知道我现在没有按比例工作。
Okay, I know that I'm not working in scale.
但是你实际上可以
But you can actually
这是你现实生活中的钥匙大小。
This is your real-life size keys.
你实际上可以打印出这个家伙，并且拥有一个完整的情节钥匙持有者。
You can actually print this motherfucker and you have a full keyholder for your plot.
因为我要把模型放在那里，你可以随意处理它们。
As I'm going to put the models there, feel free to do with them whatever you want.
这正是我喜欢这种设计方式的原因。
That's what I like about this kind of way of designing things.
我实际上不需要多想。
I actually don't need to think much.
我只是拿它做实验。
I'm just experimenting with it.
而且无论结果如何，都对我有用。
And whatever that comes out works for me.
假如我要做一个沙发，比如说
If I'm making a sofa, let's say
我总是做一个沙发只是为了展示这个技术。
I'm always making a sofa just to show the technique.
但是如果我在做沙发的过程中想到这个点子
But if I'm making a sofa and then I come up with this idea
这其实是一个巨大的胜利，因为这实际上是一个比之前更酷的点子，你知道的。
This is actually a fucking win because it's actually even a cooler idea than the previous one, you know
嗯，是的。
Well, yeah.
这足以解决一些小麻烦。
It's enough for the struggles a little bit.
它在正确放置物品方面非常有用。
It's very useful to place things correctly.
但你可以看到，这在你的公寓里随意摆放其实挺不错的。
But you can see it can be quite a nice thing to have laying around in your flat.
我喜欢它。
I love it.
但这不是我打算展示的内容。
But that wasn't what I was planning to show.
我本来打算展示我们如何让这个看起来更舒适。
I was planning to show how we can actually make this look more comfy.
所以，让我们再做一个立方体。
So, let's make another cube.
然后用这个做一个枕头。
And let's make a pillow out of this one.
从一个常规尺寸的开始吧。
Let's start with a regular sized one.
我想用这些家伙作为碰撞体。
I want to use these guys as a collider.
然后
And
我们这里需要更多的几何体。
We need more geometry here.
如果同时选择两者，按住Ctrl并拖动，你可以为每一侧添加更多的分段。
If you select both press ctrl and drag, you will add more segments to each side.
我们把这个设置成云状。
Let's put this as a cloud.
然后
And
哎呀。
Oops.
抱歉，这已经太多了。
Sorry, there's already way too many.
然后你创建一个倒角，并给它一些膨胀。
And you create a fillet and then you give this some inflation.
它会有问题，因为太薄了。
It will struggle because it's too thin.
你给它多一点空气。
You give it a little more air.
它还是有问题，因为太薄了，你需要减少一点厚度。
It still struggles because it's so thin that you need to give it a little bit less thickness.
我们试试5。
Let's try with 5.
好的，是的。
Okay, yeah.
它裂开了。
It's breaking.
不确定为什么，但我们来找找原因。
Not sure why, but let's find out.
或许试试不用倒角。
Probably let's try without fillet.
所以，我们在这里再添加一些分段。
So, let's give it a little bit more segments here.
我们需要更多的膨胀。
And we need way more inflation.
不错。
Cool.
我们有了些看起来像垫子的东西。
We have something that starts to look like a cushion.
不过我希望它薄一点。
I want it to be a bit thinner though.
让我看看是否可以让它在有倒角的情况下工作。
Let me see if I can actually get it to work with fillet.
因为我知道倒角有帮助。
Because I know that fillet helps
唉，算了。
Well, fuck it.
嗯，更多的几何体意味着我们也需要更多的膨胀。
Well, more geometry means that we need a little bit more inflation too.
我不知道为什么会有那种运动。
I don't know why it's doing that kind of motion.
也许这次我们需要更多的其他通道。
Maybe this time we need some more other passes.
让我们把阻尼调高一点。
Let's put the damping a little bit higher.
是的，这样效果更好。
Yeah, that works better.
所以，我现在要做的是，我实际上要
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to actually
首先，我要复制这个家伙。
First of all, I'm going to duplicate this motherfucker.
我要把它放到这里。
I'm going to put it here.
我要稍微旋转一下它来创建更多的副本。
I'm going to rotate it a little bit to create some more copies.
让我们对它做点什么。
Let's do something with it.
嗯，我缩小了那个，我不确定是否需要更新它。
Well, that one that I scaled down, I'm not sure if I'm going to need to update it.
但让我们进入模拟设置，比如说，跳到第60帧。
But let's go to the simulation settings and let's go to, for example, frame 60.
在这里我们要把重力打开。
And here we are going to put the gravity to be on.
两帧之前，它会关闭。
Two frames before, it's going to be off.
通过这种方式，我们会得到一个膨胀动画，然后垫子会下沉。
This way we're going to get an inflation animation and then the cushions are going to go down.
这样它们会变成垫子然后下沉。
So they become cushions then go down.
通过这种方式，你实际上可以，嗯，我觉得
And this way you can actually, well, I think
这不起作用，因为我们这里有一个碰撞体。
It's not working because we have a collider here.
但我觉得生成大量垫子是超级简单的。
But I think it's super easy to solidly generate a lot of cushions.
它仍然无法正常工作，因为那边可能还有其他隐藏的碰撞器。
It's not working still because there's probably some other hidden collider over there.
碰撞中
Colliding
这些都不是。
These are not it.
是这个。
This one.
好了，现在终于可以用了。
Okay, now it finally works.
但这很酷，因为你实际上可以创建很多这样的东西。
But this is cool because you can actually create a lot of them.
我很惊讶 Cinema 4D 处理这个的表现有多好。
I'm surprised by how well Cinema 4D handles this.
老实说，我从没想到它会表现得这么好。
Honestly, I would have never expected it to work that well.
我现在有很多这样的东西。
I have a lot of them right now.
它会稍微出点问题，但正如你所见，它仍然运行得非常非常好。
It's going to break for a little bit, but as you can see, it's still working quite, quite well.
所以现在它们膨胀起来，然后又下去了。
So now they are inflated and they go down.
你可以创造一个像枕头派对一样的场景。
You can create like a pillow party.
所以用这个技巧，我创建了这个椅子，比如你现在在右边看到的这个。
So with this technique, I created this chair, for example, that you're seeing here on the right.
我只是试着恢复它，因为它之前是这样的。
I just tried to resume it because this is how it was looking.
我觉得有些问题，因为这是我的基础形状。
And I think there's something wrong because this is my base shape.
这些是我的碰撞器，基本上就是一个盒子里面又套了一个盒子。
These are my colliders, which are just basically like a box and a box inside a box.
我觉得它现在看起来不完全一样。
I think it's currently not looking exactly the same.
啊，对，也许确实不是。我们来试试看吧。
Ah, yeah, maybe it doesn't. Let's give it a go.
所以我用了相同的技巧。我基本上创建了一个基础形状，然后让它膨胀，然后再进行碰撞。
So I did the same technique. I basically created a base shape, which I was then inflating, and then it's colliding.
不过，是的，你知道，Cinema 4D总是有调整东西的倾向。
But yeah, you know, Cinema 4D has this tendency of tweaking things.
然后突然间，当你打开一个六个月前正在处理的文件时，突然间它就无法正常工作了。
And suddenly when you open a file that you were working on from six months ago, suddenly it's not working.
是啊，这看起来很糟。我不确定这个重混是否会修复。
Yeah, this looks like shit. I'm not sure if the remix is going to get fixed.
不会的。你看，这就像，你有一个家并想要在线订购东西。
It's not. You see It's like, well, you got a home and want to order online.
不过，是的，这种形状和有机感对我来说真的很酷。老实说，我非常喜欢。
But yeah, this kind of shapes and organicness looks really cool to me. I honestly quite love it.
能够创造这些抽象外观、更有机的形状。
Being able to create these abstract-looking, more organic shapes.